usshortcodes.com 2005-12-23

# CSCA - Privacy Policy

### Common Short Code Administrator (CSCA) Privacy Agreement

* * *

CSCA, the administrator of Common Short Codes in the United States, is sensitive to the privacy concerns of those that we serve. Therefore, we have developed state-of-the art privacy programs to ensure the security and protection of the data that we collect through the provision of our mission-critical services.

Because CSCA gathers certain types of information about the users who visit the CSCA website located at [http://www.usshortcodes.com](http://www.usshortcodes.com/) (hereinafter referred to as "USSHORTCODES.COM"), we believe you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the use of the information we collect. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for CSCA. Please review the following statement to understand how the information you provide to CSCA will be treated.

1\. Information CSCA Collects

You are free to visit USSHORTCODES.COM without identifying yourself. However, if you would like more information regarding our products and services, you may be required to first register with CSCA. When you register, we will request certain business information, including your name, address, and email address. This information will enable CSCA to contact you regarding the products and services provided, as well as provides us with aggregate demographic data that CSCA uses to improve the services offered to users.

In addition to registering for an account, you may also choose to apply to lease a Common Short Code ("CSC"). To participate in this service, you will be asked a series of questions relating to you, your company and your intended uses of a CSC, should your application be successful. 

The CSCA may, from time to time, request personal information for purposes such as the provision of customer service, network management, surveys, offers of related services, and other exchanges of information.

Finally, CSCA gathers information about all users collectively, such as what areas users visit most frequently and what services users access most often. CSCA automatically logs IP addresses, session sources, and other data which tracks users' access to USSHORTCODES.COM and the other channels and CSCA sites. We analyze these logs in order to understand aggregate user behavior as well as for system performance monitoring. These logs are analyzed for the overall, aggregate trends they reveal about our customers, not for individual user behaviors.

2\. What CSCA Does With the Information It Collects.

In submitting data in an application for a CSC, you are hereby granting the CSCA, the CSC Registry, participating wireless carriers, and their respective designees and agents a license to use, copy, distribute, publish, and modify all of the data contained in Your CSC application or submitted thereafter (the "Data") for the purposes of implementing this and other related services, processing your application, notifying You of changes to the Service for archival purposes, and creating and using aggregate information about the use of CSCs wherein identifying information about You has been removed. 

In order for the CSCA and the CSC Registry to comply with the rules and policies for the administration of CSCs (which may be updated from time to time), You consent to the disclosure by Registry to the CSCA or to participating carriers, or those acting on behalf of the CSCA or participating carriers, through an interactive accessible registration database or otherwise, the Data. In addition, you acknowledge that the application for a CSC identifies those fields and Data that will be publicly disclosed or made available through the Registry's website or otherwise. You further consent to the disclosure of any Data or other information to any governmental agency upon receipt of lawful process or in compliance with any law, or to protect the rights of the CSCA.

Any other information you supply to CSCA will not be given, sold, rented, loaned, or otherwise disclosed to any third parties outside of CSCA, except when we have your express permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with legal process, (ii) enforce the service terms and conditions, or (iii) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of CSCA, its customers, or the public.

CSCA may use aggregated information to determine the demographics of our users, and to distribute statistics and general marketplace information about CSCA. These demographics will always represent aggregate information and will never identify specific users. Certain non-personal information regarding users is recorded by the operation of the Internet servers hosting the CSCA sites. CSCA may disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe the service to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

3\. What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information that allows a Web site to track the pages you've visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. CSCA uses cookies to tell when a user is a repeat visitor and to let us know how the user found the site. They also allow us to automatically link users to their personalized accounts. When you create an account, CSCA uses a cookie to store a unique, random code. CSCA only uses this code to identify you anonymously in our database and to track the pages you visit on our site. This helps us better understand and improve areas of the site that our users find valuable. CSCA also uses this code to enable you to enter various services as a member, and to visit member-restricted areas of the site without having to log in each time.

If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. Though some of the services require the use of cookies, visitors to USSHORTCODES.COM always have the option of disabling cookies via their browser preferences. You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. However, some of the services will not work if you have cookies disabled.

4\. User Options-Opt-Out

From time to time, CSCA may notify its subscribers of new products, announcements, upgrades and updates. Users may opt out of receiving these future promotional mailings by sending an email with their name to: [webmaster@usshortcodes.com](mailto:webmaster@usshortcodes.com), or by contacting us at our mailing address:

CSCA  
c/o  
NeuStar, Inc.  
46000 Center Oak Plaza  
Building X  
Sterling, VA 20166  
Attn: Legal 

CSCA reserves the right to send users email related to business practices and systems operations, such as outage notifications and quota warnings, even if the user has opted out of promotional mailings.

5\. Provision of Unsolicited Information

CSCA appreciates your feedback and suggestions. Our goal is to provide all our customers with high quality products and services. CSCA's ability to freely evaluate and, if appropriate, implement ideas and information improves the online experience for all users. Therefore, any information, feedback, data, questions, comments, suggestions, or any other material, submitted to CSCA, whether solicited or unsolicited, regarding its software, Web site or technology shall be deemed non-confidential. By providing any such material, you hereby grant CSCA an unrestricted, irrevocable, royalty-free, and perpetual right to freely, reproduce, use, disclose, modify, perform, publish, translate, create derivative works from, distribute, and display any such information you send CSCA, without limitation, for any and all commercial and non-commercial purposes. CSCA is free to use any ideas, concepts or techniques contained in this response for any purpose whatsoever including, but not limited to, developing, manufacturing, and marketing products incorporating such ideas, concepts or techniques.

6\. CSCA Privacy Statement Changes

If CSCA changes this privacy statement, we will post those changes at http://www.usshortcodes.com/ so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. By using the CSCA's services, you signify your assent to the CSCA Privacy Statement. If you do not agree to this statement, please do not use the CSCA Web site or its Services. Your continued use of the CSCA service following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

7\. Contact CSCA

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or this Web site, please contact:

Legal  
CSCA  
c/o Neustar, Inc.  
46000 Center Oak Plaza  
Building X  
Sterling, VA 20166  
email: [webmaster@usshortcodes.com](mailto:webmaster@usshortcodes.com)

© 2005 Cellular Telecommunications & Internet Association. All rights Reserved. Registrant Sublicense Agreement  |  Privacy Policy

The CSCA logo is a service mark of the Cellular Telecommunications & Internet Association. The NeuStar logo is a registered trademark of NeuStar, Inc.
